Edmund B. Chaffee Papers
Edmund B. Chaffee Papers
- Correspondence
  - 1935
    - Stor - Str (Box 49)
    - Student Volunteer Movement (Box 49)
    - Su - Sy (Box 49)
    - Tag - Tay (Box 49)
    - Teachers Guild-Union (Box 49)
    - Technocracy, Inc. (Box 49)
    - The - Tho (Box 49)
    - Thomas, Norman (Box 49)
    - Thomas, W. - Thor (Box 49)
    - Timme, Ida (Box 49)
    - Tri - Tro (Box 49)
    - Twiddy, William (Box 49)
    - Tyndal, Stanley Grant (Box 49)
    - Underwood, Mary E. (Box 49)
    - Union of Churches of Christ (Box 49)
    - Union Theological Seminary
      - Coffin, Henry Sloane, President (Box 49)
      - General File (Box 49)
      - Swift, Arthur L., Jr. (Box 49)
      - Webber, Charles C. (Box 49)
      - White, Charles T. (Box 49)
    - United Neighborhood Houses of New York, Inc., 3 folders (Box 49)
    - United State Government
      - Government of WPA, 3 folders (Box 49)
    - Universal University (Box 49)
    - Van - Vas (Box 49)
    - Versteeg, Reverent John M. (Box 49)
    - Voc - Von (Box 49)
    - Wag - Wal (Box 49)
    - Ward - Wardm (Box 49)
    - War Resisters League, 3 folders (Box 49)
    - Warr - Wars (Box 49)
    - Webster, George S. (Box 49)
    - Welfare Council of New York City (Box 49)
    - Wer - Wes (Box 49)
    - Whe - White (Box 49)
    - Whitehead, Reverend Robert C. (Box 49)
    - Wic - Wil (Box 49)
    - Wol - Woo (Box 49)
    - Workers Education Bureau of America (Box 49)
    - Workers Party of the United States (Box 49)
    - World F - U (Box 49)
    - Yag - Yal (Box 49)
    - Yergin, Reverend Howard V. (Box 49)
    - Y.M.C.A., 4 folders (Box 50)
    - Y.W.C.A., 4 folders (Box 50)
    - Younge - Youth (Box 50)
    - Unidentified (Box 50)
  - 1936
    - Allwardt, Paul (Box 50)
    - American Association for - of (Box 50)
    - American Birth Control League (Box 50)
    - American Christian Conference for German Refugees, 3 folders (Box 50)
    - American H - J (Box 50)
    - American League Against War and Fascism, 2 folders (Box 50)
    - American League to - American Women's Association (Box 50)
    - Argument (Box 50)
    - Ashley, Albert R. (Box 50)
    - Ashurst, Senator Henry P. (Box 50)
    - Barbour, Clarence A. (Box 50)
    - Barnes, George E. (Box 50)
    - Battle, George G. (Box 50)
    - Bea - Ber (Box 50)
    - Biblical Seminary in New York, The (Box 50)
    - Boe - Bos (Box 50)
    - Bricklayers, Stone Masons, Marble Masons, Terrazzo and Mosaic Workers Union Number 2 of Minnesota (Box 50)
    - Bronx Free Fellowship (Box 50)
    - Brooks, Rachel G. (Box 50)
    - Brookwood (Box 50)
    - Broun, Heywood (Box 50)
    - Bucknell University (Box 50)
    - Cam - Car (Box 50)
    - Central Conference on American Rabbis (Box 50)
    - Chaffee, Family of (Box 50)
    - Cham - Chi (Box 50)
    - "Christian American" and Bible Student (Box 50)
    - Christian Century, The (Box 50)
    - Christo - Chu (Box 50)
    - Cit - Civ (Box 50)
    - Clinchy, Everett R. (Box 50)
    - Columbia University (Box 50)
    - Committee for - to (Box 50)
    - Commo - Commu (Box 50)
    - Consumer C - U (Box 50)
    - Coo - Cor (Box 50)
    - Davis - John W. (Box 50)
    - Des Moines Independent School District (Box 50)
    - Drysdale, Mrs. J. M. (Box 50)
    - Dudley, J. M. (Box 50)
    - Durant, Will (Box 50)
    - Durham, "Gene" (Box 50)
    - Eastern Clergy Bureau (Box 50)
    - Eddy, Sherwood (Box 50)
    - Elliott, Phillips (Box 50)
    - Emergency Peace Campaign (Box 50)
    - Expositor and the Homiletic Review, The (Box 50)
    - Fam - Farr (Box 50)
    - Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America, 5 folders (Box 50)
    - Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies (Box 50)
    - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 3 folders (Box 50)
    - Ferrero - Salitto Defense Conference (Box 50)
    - Fig - Fis (Box 50)
    - Fla - Fly (Box 50)
    - Forb - Fort (Box 50)
    - Fosdick, Harry Emerson (Box 50)
    - Fra - Fri (Box 50)
    - Gol - Goo (Box 50)
    - Greater New York Federation of Churches, 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Gull - Guin (Box 50)
    - Hartford Theological Seminary, Hornell Hart (Box 50)
    - Hem - Hen (Box 50)
    - Holmes, John Haynes (Box 50)
    - Hol - Hop (Box 50)
    - International Relief Association (Box 50)
    - Jac - Jap (Box 50)
    - Jennes, Mary (Box 50)
    - Jenney, Ray F. (Box 50)
    - Jewish Theological Seminary of New York (Box 50)
    - John Hope Memorial Fund Committee (Box 50)
    - Kam - Kat (Box 50)
    - Kennedy, Ann Cochran (Box 50)
    - Kips Bay Neighborhood Conference (Box 50)
    - Labor Temple
      - Affirmations, Notices of Church Services (Box 50)
      - Annual Reports, Statements, Audits (Box 50)
      - Budget, Allocation of Funds, Finances, 3 folders (Box 50)
      - Committee Meetings, Notices and Responses, Arrangements for (Box 50)
      - Contributions to, Appeals and Responses, Thank You Notes, 4 folders (Box 50)
      - Employment Inquiries and Recommendations January, March-May (Box 50)
      - Employment Inquiries and Recommendations June-July, September (Box 51)
      - Maintenance and Repairs, Supplies and Equipment (Box 51)
      - Programs and Activities, 4 folders (Box 51)
      - Solicitations for Temple Business, 3 folders (Box 51)
      - Work Schedules and Instructions to Personnel, 3 folders (Box 51)
    - Lanning, Reverend Jesse H. (Box 51)
    - Lea - Lei (Box 51)
    - Lewis, John L., United Mine Workers of America (Box 51)
    - Lin - Lis (Box 51)
    - Log - Low (Box 51)
    - Lydenberg, Mrs. H. M. (Box 51)
    - Magill, Reverend Andrew (Box 51)
    - Mandelbaum, Samuel, New York State Senator (Box 51)
    - Marcantonio, Vito, United States Congress, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - March of Time, The (Box 51)
    - Mart - Mas (Box 51)
    - McA - McE (Box 51)
    - McSwain, John J., United States Congressman (Box 51)
    - Merril - Merrit (Box 51)
    - Methodist Episcopal Church, Church School Publications (Box 51)
    - Metropolitan Host - Youth (Box 51)
    - Mille - Mills (Box 51)
    - Ministers' Union (Box 51)
    - Minnesota State Conference of Social Work (Box 51)
    - Mitchell, Professor Lewis (Box 51)
    - Moh - Mos (Box 51)
    - National Child - Committee on (Box 51)
    - National Conference of Jews and Christians, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - National Negro - Probation (Box 51)
    - National Religion and Labor Foundation (Box 51)
    - National Unemployment League (Box 51)
    - Nea - Nei (Box 51)
    - New England-Jersey College (Box 51)
    - New Jersey Council of Religious Education (Box 51)
    - New School for Social Research (Box 51)
    - New York City
      - Christian Endeavor Union (Box 51)
      - Committee of Social Scientists and Workers (Box 51)
      - Mission Society (Box 51)
    - New York (City of)
      - Board of Education (Box 51)
      - City College of New York (Box 51)
      - Department of Buildings (Box 51)
      - Department of Parks, Moses, Robert, Commissioner (Box 51)
      - Home Relief Unit (Box 51)
      - Office of the Mayor, La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Box 51)
      - Police Department (Box 51)
    - New York E - H (Box 51)
    - New York State Conference on Marriage and the Family (Box 51)
    - New York State Division of Alcoholic Beverage Control (Box 51)
    - New York State P - T (Box 51)
    - Nicholas, Dewitt (Box 51)
    - Niebuhr, H. Richard (Box 51)
    - Non - Nor (Box 51)
    - Nye, Gerald P., United States Senator (Box 51)
    - O'Shay, Madeline (Box 51)
    - Page, Kirby (Box 51)
    - Partlow, John D. (Box 51)
    - Peale, Norman Vincent (Box 51)
    - Pell, Mrs. F. Livingston, Jr. (Box 51)
    - Peoples' Committee Mandate (Box 51)
    - Per - Pew (Box 51)
    - Phillips, Wilbur C. (Box 51)
    - Presbyterian Church in the United States of America
      - Board of National Missions and Board of Foreign Missions, 2 folders (Box 51)
      - Office of the General Assembly (Box 51)
      - Synod of Indiana (Box 51)
      - Synod of New York (Box 51)
      - Synod of Ohio, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Presbyterian Fellowship for Social Action (Box 51)
    - Presbyterian Tribune, The, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Presbytery of New York
      - Bartlett, Maitland Stated Clerk (Box 51)
      - Church Extension Committee
        - Savage, Theodore, Executive Secretary, 4 folders (Box 51)
      - Department of Christian Education (Box 51)
      - Social Service Committee (Box 52)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 52)
    - Proh - Prov (Box 52)
    - Pub - Pus (Box 52)
    - Rath, Reverend Theodore (Box 52)
    - Rec - Rel (Box 52)
    - Rhoad, Reverend Frank T. (Box 52)
    - Richards, Edward C. M. (Box 52)
    - Richards, George H., 3 folders (Box 52)
    - Rob - Roy (Box 52)
    - Rutgers University (Box 52)
    - Rutherford, Elizabeth (Mars Hill College) (Box 52)
    - Sad - Sav (Box 52)
    - Schappes, Morris U. (Box 52)
    - Schieffelin, Bayard (Box 52)
    - Sco - Scr (Box 52)
    - Sibley, Harper (Box 52)
    - Sik - Sim (Box 52)
    - Sirovich, William I., United States Congressman (Box 52)
    - Smith College (Box 52)
    - Soc - Sou (Box 52)
    - Speers, Reverend Thomas Guthrie (Box 52)
    - Stee - Stew (Box 52)
    - Sto - Str (Box 52)
    - Stud - Stuy (Box 52)
    - Subke, Reverend Walter Carl (Box 52)
    - Summers, Hatton W., United States Congressman (Box 52)
    - Sunday School Board (Box 52)
    - Syracuse University (Box 52)
    - Taylor, Mary Sanford (Box 52)
    - Teachers' Guild-Union (Box 52)
    - Technocracy Incorporated (Box 52)
    - The - Tho (Box 52)
    - United Labor May Day Committee (Box 52)
    - Union Theological Seminary, 3 folders (Box 52)
    - United Committee to Aid Vermont Marble Workers (Box 52)
    - United Neighborhood Houses of New York, 2 folders (Box 52)
    - United States Works Progress Association, 4 folders (Box 52)
    - Universal Christian Council (Box 52)
    - Van Hooser, Ruby (Box 52)
    - Verit, W. E. (Box 52)
    - Vieth, Paul H. (Box 52)
    - Voc - Voe (Box 52)
    - War Resisters' League (Box 52)
    - Washington and Jefferson College (Box 52)
    - Web - Wen (Box 52)
    - Westminster Foundation at Ohio State University (Box 52)
    - Wil - Wis (Box 52)
    - White - Whitn (Box 52)
    - Wom - Wor (Box 52)
    - World Alliance - Friendship (Box 52)
    - Yale University Divinity School (Box 52)
    - Yergin, Reverend Howard (Box 52)
    - Yorkville Forum (Box 52)
    - Y.M.C.A. (Box 52)
    - Y.W.C.A. (Box 52)
    - Young Peoples' Society (Box 52)
    - Unidentified (Box 52)
  - No Date
    - B, unidentified (Box 52)
  - To and from others
    - 1936
      - A - Ho, 15 folders (Box 52)
      - Hu - Y, 26 folders (Box 53)
      - Unidentified (Box 53)
    - 1937
      - A - W, 11 folders (Box 53)
    - 1939
      - T (Box 53)
    - 1941
      - R (Box 53)
- Subject files
  - Banking Crisis, The, 1932-1933; undated (Box 54)
  - Bibliographies (Box 54)
  - Bills and Receipts
    - 1920 (Box 54)
    - 1921 (Box 54)
    - 1922 (Box 54)
    - 1923 (Box 54)
    - 1924 (Box 54)
    - 1925, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - 1926 (Box 54)
    - 1927, 4 folders (Box 54)
    - 1928, 4 folders (Box 54)
    - 1929, 4 folders (Box 54)
    - Trip to Europe, 1930 (Box 54)
    - 1931, 4 folders (Box 55)
    - 1932, 4 folders (Box 55)
    - 1933, 4 folders (Box 55)
    - 1934 (Box 55)
    - 1935 (Box 55)
    - 1936 (Box 55)
  - Chi Alpha, 1922; 1924-1926 (Box 55)
  - Excerpts from Sermons and Articles, Pres. Trib., 1935-1936 (Box 55)
  - Holly Union High School, 1906 (Box 55)
  - Immortality, 1926; 1929,; 1934,; undated; 3 folders (Box 55)
  - Inventories, 1929 (Box 55)
  - Labor Temple
    - Budget A, April 1932-1933 (Box 55)
    - Sunday School (curriculum and enrollment, 1921-1929 (Box 55)
  - Labor (Box 56)
  - Memorial Tributes and Sympathy Cards, 1936 (Box 56)
  - Neighborhood Houses, 1925 (Box 56)
  - Palestine, 1918-1920 (Box 56)
  - Passport Applications, February 1918-1919 (Box 56)
  - Poetry and Song Hits, 1922; 1934-1936 (Box 56)
  - The Presbytery of New York, 1915 (Box 56)
  - Programs, 1916; 1933-1936 (Box 56)
  - Questionnaire (Box 56)
  - Reports, 1933; 1936,; undated (Box 56)
  - School Report Card, about, 1902 (Box 56)
  - Technocracy, 1930-1935 (Box 57)
  - War Prevention, 1929-1935 (Box 57)
- Manuscripts
  - About Chaffee
    - 1916, 1932, 1936, undated (Box 58)
  - Articles by
    - "Capitalism, Communism and Prophetic Religion", undated (Box 58)
    - "Challenge of Communism, The", undated (Box 58)
    - "F.O.R. Swarthmore Conference, The", undated (Box 58)
    - "France viz the Arabs", undated (Box 58)
    - "Is Religion a Bound or a Barrier?", undated (Box 58)
    - "Korean Situation Today, The", undated (Box 58)
    - "Labor Temple", undated (Box 58)
    - "Labor Temple, an Attempt of the Church to Solve Problems of Today", undated (Box 58)
    - "Manning vs. Lindsay", 1930 (Box 58)
    - "My Personal Creed", 1916 (Box 58)
    - "Near East Relief, The - The Sequel", undated (Box 58)
    - "Opium and Morphine in China", undated (Box 58)
    - "Pacifism and the Class War--The Issue in the F.O.R.", undated (Box 58)
    - "Red Cross 'Carrying On,' A", undated (Box 58)
    - "Saving the Constitution", undated (Box 58)
    - "Savonarola", 1914 (Box 58)
    - "Some Adventures in Palestine", 1919 (Box 58)
    - "Some Recent Lives of Jesus", undated (Box 58)
    - "Suicide", undated (Box 58)
    - "Special Correspondence, June 3, 1936," Christian Century (Box 58)
    - "Sun Yat Sen A Chinese Robert Bruce", undated (Box 58)
    - "Technocracy, An Interpretation and a Criticism", undated (Box 58)
    - "Technocracy's Warning", undated (Box 58)
    - "Testing Fellowship Ideals in Jerusalem", undated (Box 58)
    - "Visit to the Home of Tagore, A", 1920 (Box 58)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 58)
  - Books by
    - "Protestant Churches and the Industrial Crisis, The", undated (Box 58)
  - Book Reviews
    - Business and the Church, by Jerome Davis (Box 58)
    - Does Civilization Need Religion? by Reinhold Niebuhr (Box 58)
    - Does Man Survive? by George Lindsay Johnson (Box 58)
    - Jesus, by Henri Barbusse (Box 58)
    - John White of Mashonaland, by C. F. Andrews (Box 58)
    - Preachers Present Arms, by Ray H. Abrams (Box 58)
    - Spengler’s Second Volume, 1929 (Box 58)
    - Thayer's Life of Washinqton, undated (Box 58)
    - Hymn, "Be Thou Supreme" (Box 58)
  - Lectures
    - "The Mind of Christ in a Machine Age" (Box 59)
    - "New Vistas in Science" (Box 59)
    - "Our Present Day Civilization in the Light of the Teachings of Jesus" I-VI (Box 59)
    - Untitled
      - Y.W.C.A. Conference, 1st through 5th Periods (Box 59)
      - Y.W.C.A. Conference, Lectures II-III (Box 59)
    - Outlines, 1917; 1922,; 1934,; undated; 4 folders (Box 59)
  - Notes
    - Undated (Box 59)
    - School, 1914; 1915,; 1916; 3 folders (Box 59)
  - Pamphlets
    - The Captain's Book, with others, 1918 (Box 59)
  - Papers
    - "Distinctive Elements in the Religion of Jesus" (Box 59)
    - "How Shall We Teach Morality", 1915 (Box 59)
    - "My Personal Creed", 1916 (Box 59)
    - "Personal Immortality" (Box 59)
    - "What Has Psychical Research Accomplished?" (Box 59)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 59)
  - Prayers
    - Prayer (an untitled prayer by Chaffee) (Box 59)
  - Reports
    - 1932, undated (Box 59)
  - Sermons
    - Age of Plenty, The (Box 60)
    - American and Japan, Some Facts--Not Propaganda (Box 60)
    - American Proletariat, The (Box 60)
    - America's Way Out (Box 60)
    - Are Modernists Destructive? (Box 60)
    - Asoka, One of the World's Great (Box 60)
    - Backgrounds of Scientific and Psychological Thought in our Churches Affecting the Presentation of the Cause of Foreign Missions (Box 60)
    - Book of Daniel and Our Life Today, The (Box 60)
    - Book of Revelation, The (Box 60)
    - Can We Achieve an Ethical Society by Unethical Methods? (Box 60)
    - Can We Change Human Nature? (Box 60)
    - Capital Punishment (Box 60)
    - Changing Mood of Science, The (Box 60)
    - Christian Answer to a Despairing World, The (Box 60)
    - Christian Men in a Pagan World (Box 60)
    - Christianity and Profits (Box 60)
    - Christianity and Rent (Box 60)
    - Christianity and Six Per Cent Interest (Box 60)
    - Christianity and the Industrial Crisis (Box 60)
    - Christianity and War (Box 60)
    - Christianity and World Unrest (Box 60)
    - Christianity, a Proletarian Movement (Box 60)
    - Christianity in a Capitalist World (Box 60)
    - Christians in a Lost World (Box 60)
    - Christians and War (Box 60)
    - Christ's Message for a Day of Crisis (Box 60)
    - Church and a Changing Order, The (Box 60)
    - Church and the Labor Movement, The (Box 60)
    - Church and the Social Challenge, The (Box 60)
    - Church and War Resistance, The (Box 60)
    - Churches and Politics (Box 60)
    - Communism and Religion (Box 60)
    - Communism, Hope or Menace? (Box 60)
    - Communism in the Light of the Christian Ethic (Box 60)
    - Communism--Its Truth and Error (Box 60)
    - Communism or Fascism, Must We Choose? (Box 60)
    - Concept of Equality, The (Box 60)
    - Cooperative Movement, The (Box 60)
    - Cosmological Argument for the Existence of God in the Light of Recent Science, The (Box 60)
    - Courage (Box 60)
    - Cross and Its Meaning for Us, The (Box 60)
    - Cross and the Revolution, The (Box 60)
    - Democracy, An Appraisal (Box 60)
    - Did Jesus Really Live? (Box 60)
    - Did Jesus Teach Anything New? (Box 60)
    - Dr. Fosdick and the Presbyterians (Box 60)
    - Do You Believe in Free Speech? (Box 60)
    - Does Civilization Need Religion? (Box 60)
    - Does Labor Need a God? (Box 60)
    - Duty of the Church in the Industrial Crisis, The (Box 60)
    - Economic Waste--A Moral Issue (Box 60)
    - Economics Is Not Enough (Box 60)
    - Energies of Men, The (Box 60)
    - Ethic of Jesus, The (Box 60)
    - Ethics and Propaganda (Box 60)
    - Ethics of Propaganda, The (Box 60)
    - Exploitation--The Sun of the Ages (Box 60)
    - Fascism Fails (Box 61)
    - Fascism--From the Ethical Standpoint (Box 61)
    - Fear Not (Box 61)
    - Finding the Good Life (Box 61)
    - First Step Toward the New Social Order, The or Child Likeness, The Door to the Kingdom of God (Box 61)
    - Free Speech (Box 61)
    - Galilean Carpenter and the Industrial Crisis, The (Box 61)
    - Gandhi (Box 61)
    - Gandhi or Dynamite (Box 61)
    - God Is (Box 61)
    - Good Friday Day Sermon (Box 61)
    - Government in Business (Box 61)
    - Great Social Sin (Box 61)
    - Headed for War (Box 61)
    - High Power Machinery and Its Social Consequences (Box 61)
    - Holism and Evolution (Box 61)
    - Home Missions and "Community Work" (Box 61)
    - If War Comes (Box 61)
    - Immortality--Fact or Fancy (Box 61)
    - Implications of the Present Economic Situation for the Program of the Church and Neighborhood House (Box 61)
    - Is Christianity Democratic? (Box 61)
    - Is Christianity Practicable? (Box 61)
    - Is Depression Over? (Box 61)
    - Is God Any Guide for Today? (Box 61)
    - Is One Race Better Than Another? (Box 61)
    - Is Progress an Illusion? (Box 61)
    - Is Science Passing? (Box 61)
    - Is the United States an Empire? (Box 61)
    - Is the World a Soul-less Mechanism? (Box 61)
    - Is There a Future Life? Is There a God? (Box 61)
    - Isaiah (Box 61)
    - It Is Finished (Box 61)
    - Italy and the League of Nations (Box 61)
    - Jesus and Marx, Alike and Different (Box 61)
    - Jesus and the Industrial Crisis (Box 61)
    - Jesus and the Romans (Box 61)
    - Jesus Teaching Concerning the Kingdom of God (Box 61)
    - Jesus, The Revolutionist (Box 61)
    - John Ball, The Mad Priest of Kent (Box 61)
    - Labor and the Christian Conscience (Box 61)
    - Labor Needs a God (Box 61)
    - Labor Sunday Message (Box 61)
    - Life As An Adventure (Box 61)
    - Limitations of Physical Science (Box 61)
    - Living Wage, a Mellifluous Phrase, The (Box 61)
    - Lost World, A (Box 62)
    - Machine Age and Religion, The (Box 62)
    - Man and Machinery (Box 62)
    - Menace of the Closed Mind, The (Box 62)
    - Method of Bringing in the Kingdom, The (Box 62)
    - Mind of Christ in a Day of Crisis, The (Box 62)
    - Moral Issue in Taxation, The (Box 62)
    - Moral Issues in This Campaign (Box 62)
    - Moral Issues in West Virginia (Box 62)
    - More About Gandhi (Box 62)
    - More About Technocracy (Box 62)
    - Motives of Men, The (Box 62)
    - My Idea of God (Box 62)
    - Nature of the Christian Ethic (Box 62)
    - New Days (Box 62)
    - Next War, The--What Will It Be Like? (Box 62)
    - Optimism True and False (Box 62)
    - Origin of the Social Gospel, The (Box 62)
    - Our American Debt Structure (Box 62)
    - Our Greatest Collective Sin (Box 62)
    - Our Message for Today (Box 62)
    - Pacifism of the Early Christians, The (Box 62)
    - Pacifism and the Social Revolution (Box 62)
    - Peace and Brotherhood (Box 62)
    - Peace--How to Attain It (Box 62)
    - People and the Corporations, The (Box 62)
    - Personal Virtues and the Social Gospel (Box 62)
    - Philosophy of Oswald G. Spengler (Box 62)
    - Politics and Preachers (Box 62)
    - Poverty (causes of) (Box 62)
    - Prejudice Against Immortality, The (Box 62)
    - Progress, A Fact or a Fancy (Box 62)
    - Prohibition--A Summary and a Forecast (Box 62)
    - Propaganda--Is It Ethical? (Box 62)
    - Property in the Light of the Teaching and Spirit of Jesus (Box 62)
    - Prophets, The (Box 62)
    - Prosperity--Fact or Myth? (Box 62)
    - Radical Parties and the American Voter (Box 62)
    - Radical’s Thanksgiving, A (Box 62)
    - Reflections on Armistice Day (Box 62)
    - Religion and Evolution (Box 62)
    - Religion and Exploitation, A Study in Origins (Box 62)
    - Religion and Revolution (Box 62)
    - Religion and the God-State (Box 62)
    - Religion and the Materialistic Conception of History (Box 63)
    - Religion and the Modern State (Box 63)
    - Religion and the New Biology (Box 63)
    - Religion and the New Physics (Box 63)
    - Religion and the New Psychology (Box 63)
    - Religion and the New Sociology (Box 63)
    - Religious and Philosophical Basis of Free Speech, The (Box 63)
    - Religious Mind in a Day of Crisis, The (Box 63)
    - Religious Sanctions of the Doctrine of Free Speech (Box 63)
    - Resolutions for Radicals (Box 63)
    - Resolved that Labor Needs a God (Box 63)
    - Revolt of Asia, The (Box 63)
    - Role of Machinery in the Present Crisis, The (Box 63)
    - Roosevelt in May (Box 63)
    - Science and Religion--Are They in Conflict? (Box 63)
    - Shall We Have Free Speech? (Box 63)
    - Shock Troops of Peace (Box 63)
    - Signs of the Times, The (Box 63)
    - Social Hope of the Ancient World, The (Box 63)
    - Social Trends Report, The (Box 63)
    - Some Conditions in North America That Affect the Foreign Missionary Enterprises of the Church (Box 63)
    - Some Issues That Confront the Ministry Today (Box 63)
    - Some Peace Axioms (Box 63)
    - Some Things Worth While (Box 63)
    - Spear Head of Fascism, The (Box 63)
    - Spiritual Needs of Modern Men (Box 63)
    - Spiritual Resources of a Radical, The (Box 63)
    - Student Movement in China, The (Box 63)
    - Strength of Capitalism (Box 63)
    - Supreme Court, The Constitution and the People, The (Box 63)
    - Supreme Demand of Our High Power Age (Box 63)
    - Teachings of Jesus and Our Social Order, The (Box 63)
    - Test of a Christian, The (Box 63)
    - Three Great Issues Facing the Church (Box 63)
    - Throwing Your Vote Away (Box 63)
    - Tired Radicals (Box 63)
    - Totalitarian State, The (Box 63)
    - Tribute to Moses, A (Box 63)
    - Two Years of Roosevelt (Box 63)
    - Unemployment, Menace or Hope? (Box 63)
    - Union Course (Box 63)
    - Unpardonable Sin, The (Box 63)
    - War and One Hundred Percent Pacifism (Box 63)
    - War and the Christian Conscience (Box 63)